# Soundarya Ramesh

(Last Updated: September, 2024)

## RESEARCH SUMMARY

My research interests are broadly in the realm of sensor data analysis for enabling novel applications. Currently, in my PhD, I am investigating the utility of audio sensor data for security, including proposing robust authentication methods, launching attacks, and designing defenses against eavesdropping. Looking ahead, I aim to explore complex sensing challenges in emerging technologies such as AR/VR and wearables, as well as in the healthcare domain.

#### CONTACT

E-mail: sramesh@comp.nus.edu.sg Website: https://soundaryaramesh.github.io

#### **EDUCATION**

# National University of Singapore

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science

Advisors: Jun Han and Chan Mun Choon

Expected Graduation: Dec 2024

## National Institute of Technology Karnataka, India

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology

Jul 2014 - May 2018

Aug 2018 - Present

Current GPA: 4.92/5

GPA: 9.01/10

#### CONFERENCE PAPERS

- MagTracer: Detecting GPU Cryptojacking Attacks via Magnetic Leakage Signals. Rui Xiao, Tianyu Li, Soundarya Ramesh, Jun Han, Jinsong Han. **ACM MobiCom 2023**.
- *TickTock*: Detecting Mic Status in Laptops Leveraging Electromagnetic Leakage of Clock Signals. Soundarya Ramesh, Ghozali Hadi, Sihun Yang, Chan Mun Choon, Jun Han. **ACM CCS 2022**.
- Acoustics to the Rescue: Physical Key Inference Attack Revisited.
  Soundarya Ramesh, Rui Xiao, Anindya Maiti, Jong Taek Lee, Harini Ramprasad, Ananda Kumar,
  Murtuza Jadliwala, Jun Han. USENIX Security 2021.
- Neuro-Symbolic Execution: Augmenting Symbolic Execution with Neural Constraints.
  Shen Shiqi, Shweta Shinde, <u>Soundarya Ramesh</u>, Abhik Roychoudhury, Prateek Saxena. NDSS 2019.

#### WORKSHOP PUBLICATIONS

- Your Mic Leaks Too Much: A Double-Edged Sword for Security Soundarya Ramesh. ACM MobiSys Rising Stars 2024.
   Best Presentation Award
- RampScope: Ramp-level Localization of Shared Mobility Devices using Sidewalk Ramps. Jonghyuk Yun\*, Gyuyeon Kim\*, Soundarya Ramesh, Jun Han. ACM HotMobile 2023.
- Listen to Your Key: Towards Acoustics-based Physical Key Inference.
  Soundarya Ramesh, Harini Ramprasad, Jun Han. ACM HotMobile 2020.
  Media Coverage: ACM News, Forbes, Scientific American, HackerNews, Mashable and over 25,000 views on YouTube

• SoundUAV: Towards Delivery Drone Authentication via Acoustic Noise Fingerprinting. Soundarya Ramesh, Thomas Pathier, Jun Han. ACM DroNet 2019.

#### INDUSTRY CONFERENCES

• RollBack - A New Time-Agnostic Replay Attack Against the Automotive Remote Keyless Entry Systems.

Levente Csikor, Hoon Wei Lim, Jun Wen Wong, <u>Soundarya Ramesh</u>, Rohini Poolat Parameswarath, Chan Mun Choon. **Black Hat USA 2022**.

## **POSTERS**

- RampScope: Ramp-level Localization of Shared Mobility Devices using Sidewalk Ramps. Jonghyuk Yun\*, Gyuyeon Kim\*, Soundarya Ramesh, Jun Han. ACM HotMobile 2023. Best Poster Award
- SoundUAV: Fingerprinting Acoustic Emanations for Delivery Drone Authentication.
  Soundarya Ramesh, Thomas Pathier, Jun Han. ACM MobiSys 2019.
  Best Poster Runner-up Award

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

# Research Intern at Google, Mountain View

May-Aug 2022

Speech Processing for AR Glasses as part of the Augmented Language Team

Hosts: Chiong Lai, Mathieu Parvaix (co-host)

## Research Intern at System Security Lab, NUS

May-Dec 2017

Augmenting Symbolic Execution with Constraints Approximated as a Neural Network

Host: Prateek Saxena

# Research Intern at Cryptography and Information Security Lab, IISc

May-Jun 2016

Development of Efficient Protocols for Graph Consensus Problem in Directed Graphs

Host: Arpita Patra

## HONORS AND AWARDS

| • Google PhD Fellowship (under Mobile Computing research area)                   | 2021-2024 |
|--|-----------|
| • NUS School of Computing Dean's Graduate Research Achievement Award             | 2022      |
| • Placed on the Honor List of Student Tutors for Excellence in Teaching          | 2022      |
| • Graduate Research Fellowship, National University of Singapore                 | 2018-2022 |
| $\bullet$ $Research$ Forum $Award$ at the Deep Learning & Security Workshop, NUS | 2017      |
| • Indian Academy of Sciences Fellowship  | 2016      |
|  |           |

## INVITED TALKS

| • Microsoft Research, Bengaluru, India (hosted by Rohan Gandhi) | Aug 2024 |
|---|----------|
| • SiNRG Lab (led by Prof. Romit Roy Choudhury), UIUC            | May 2024 |
| • Acoustical Society of America Meeting in Ottawa, Canada       | May 2024 |
| • Safesforce Cloud Security Assurance Team, Seattle             | Sep 2023 |
| • NESL Lab (led by Prof. Mani Srivastava), UCLA                 | Feb 2023 |

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages**: Python, Matlab, C/C++

Technical Expertise: Ambient Audio Analysis, Speech Enhancement, Signal Processing, Machine

Learning, Electromagnetic Signal-based Sensing

Sensors: Microphones, Inertial Measurement Units (IMUs), Optical Sensors (Cameras, PPGs)

Hardware: 3D-Printing and Prototyping, Development using Respeaker Microphone Array, USRP

B210 Software Defined Radio, Raspberry Pi and Arduino

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

• Teaching Assistant for CS4222 Wireless Networks

*Spring 2022* 

• Teaching Assistant for CS3103 Computer Networks Practice

Fall 2021

• Teaching Assistant for CS3235 Computer Security

Spring 2020

• Teaching Assistant for CS5476 IoT Security

Fall 2019, Fall 2020

### PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

# Student Reviewing Member

• Master of Computing Admission in the School of Computing, NUS (2022)

# Program Committee Member / Reviewer

- ACM MobiCom 2024 S3 Workshop
- ACM MobiSys 2024 Artifact Evaluation
- ACM IMWUT 2023
- ACM Transactions on Internet of Things 2022

## External Reviewer

- Conferences: S&P 2024, Security 2024, IPSN 2024, SenSys 2020-2023, IoTDI 2020-2022, ICDCS 2020-2022, COMSNETS 2020-2021, WiSec 2019, MobiSys 2019, 2024
- Workshops: HotMobile 2022, 2024